Selected Compositions of Peter Easley
Yale University Music Library
Selected Compositions of Peter Easley
1943-1965
Misc. Ms. 52
Yale University Music Library
3
(3 boxes)
Selected compositions of the American composer Peter Easley (1927-1974)
Easley, Peter, 1927-1974
Conditions Governing Access
Easley's compositions are open to researchers by appointment. There are no restricted materials in the collection. Please contact the Special Collections staff to schedule an appointment.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The collection was established in the Music Library of Yale University by Dorothy Easley in 1974.
Arrangement
Arranged in alphabetical order by title.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains manuscript scores and parts for 11 musical compositions by Peter Easley. Among the works included are concertos for piano and cello, sonatas for piano and violin, 2 symphonies, a string quartet, and settings for voice of texts by Edna St. Vincent Millay and Paul Verlaine. Some of the manuscripts are stored in rolls rather than flat, and some are negative stencils.
Biographical / Historical
Peter Easley, whose real name was Ronald Merl Easley, Jr., was born in 1927 in Salem, Massachusetts. He attended Yale College from 1944 to 1946, completing two semesters, and finished his schooling at the University of New Mexico. He died in 1974.
Concertos (Piano) -- Scores; Concertos (Cello) -- Scores; Symphonies -- Scores; Millay, Edna St. Vincent, 1892-1950 -- Musical settings; Verlaine, Paul, 1844-1896 -- Musical settings
- Concerto For Piano And Orchestra, 1960
  - Score (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General
    (signed holograph, rolled)
  - Score (Box 1, Folder 2)
    (photographic reproduction)
  - Score, 3rd movement only (Box 1, Folder 3)
    (photographic reproduction, rolled)
  - Score, 2 pianos, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Concerto For Violincello And Orchestra, 1961
  - Score (Box 1, Folder 5)
    (signed holograph, cello part only is a negative stencil; rolled)
  - Score (Box 2, Folder 1)
    (negative stencil, rolled)
  - Score (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Cello and Piano Reduction (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Cello and Piano Reduction (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Cello and Piano Reduction (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Cello part only (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Cello part only (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Cello part only, 1st movement only (Box 1, Folder 12)
    (incomplete rough draft)
- Mass In D Minor For Mixed Choir In 8 Parts, à capella, SSAATTBB, 1954
  - Score (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Score (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Score (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Trumpet part only (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Scope and Contents
    Credo
    2 Glorias (1 incomplete)
    Kyrie
- 3-Preludes For Piano, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  (signed holograph)
- Quartet In D Minor (Strings), 1945
  - Score (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Parts (Box 3, Folder 7)
    (photographic reproductions)
- Quintet For Alto And Strings On Poems Of Edna St. Vincent Millay, 1965
  - Alto and Piano Reduction (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Alto and Piano Reduction, 1st movement only, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - 1st Violin part only (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Sonata For Contralto Voice And Piano On Poem Of Paul Verlaine, 1913-1944
  - Score (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Score (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Score (Box 3, Folder 13)
    (negative stencil)
- Sonata For Piano In C Minor, 1948
  (Revised 1949)
  - Negative Stencil (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Sonata For Violin And Piano In A, 1945
  - Score (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Score, 1st movement only (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Violin part only (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Symphony In B, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Symphony No. 3, 1955
  - Score (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Score (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Score (Box 3, Folder 21)